Joel Cribby

104-1236 Pandora Ave, Victoria BC, V8V 3R4 | 778-677-9799 | joelcribby@gmail.com

Objective

Passionate and dedicated Software Developer with a history in Web Application Design and DevOps system management. Quick learner that excels in fast-paced environments that require diligent attention to detail and a focus on providing efficient solutions to new challenges. Experienced in the Agile development lifecycle and capable of owning a project and seeing it through to completion.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF VICTORIA

· Degree: Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Date Completed: January 2020

Skills & Abilities

RELEVANT SKILLS

- Excellent knowledge of C#, HTML5/CSS3, and XMI.
- · Well versed in Agile Development
- · Competent in Unit / Automated Testing

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Skilled in use of Windows dev environment tools such as Visual Studio, IIS and SSMS
- Capable of working both independently and in a team

- Fundamental understanding of database systems and queries using SQL
- Proficient in the use of object-oriented programming
- Strong understanding of CI/CD and DevOps systems
- Proficient in the development of RESTful APIs as well as the Angular framework

Experience

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | ENCOREFX | JAN 2020 - MAR 2020

- Managed and implemented DevOps improvements and maintenance with the objective of streamlining development systems and increasing efficiency.
- Utilized Gitlab CI/CD and IIS to design and coordinate web application deployments to various build environments.
- · Responsible for researching and introducing new methods for increasing productivity and reducing build times.
- Implemented a shared cache server for runners using MinIO object storage and Docker to allow for faster downloading of pipeline artifacts.
- Introduced automated semantic versioning of all projects to allow for quicker and easier release note generation.
- Handled all DevOps related refactorization when migrating from a monolithic code base to a microservice structure.
- · Led an initiative to consolidate all CI related YAML files into a shared script storage.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN | ENCOREFX | MAY 2020 - SEP 2020

- · Developed features and tests for a web application across the entire stack.
- · Utilized the Angular framework ecosystem to introduce and develop test-driven features.
- Researched and implemented new infrastructure improvements and presented findings to the team and stakeholders.
- Designed reactive and user-friendly web page components using HTML and CSS
- Introduced fixtures for testing new features using unit testing and Selenium automated testing development methodologies.
- Improved upon and generated new SQL queries using Entity framework and SMSS for interacting with the 3rd party database.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER CO-OP | AML OCEANOGRAPHIC LTD. | APR 2018 - JAN 2019

- · Worked independently as the sole on-site software developer for AML with the objective of developing, updating, and designing company software using MVVM framework.
- · Developed and designed an application using C# and XML.
- · Contributed to user experience decisions as well as helped maintain the project management workflow.
- · Implemented multiple third-party APIs for data visualization including Telerik and Google Maps
- · Worked to implement Wi-Fi and Bluetooth connectivity between hardware and software.
- · Utilized Atlassian products such as JIRA for project management and user story generation.

References

KYLE MORRIS | ENCOREFX | SUPERVISOR

· Position: Project Leader

· Email: kyle@nexusfusion.com

· Phone #: 250-514-9982

DUSTIN OLENDER | AML OCEANOGRAPHIC | SUPERVISOR

· Position: Director of ISO Implementation

· Email: dustinolender@amloceanograpic.com

Phone #: 250-656-0771 ext. 208